JACOB LINDSEY FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

jacob.lindsey88@gmail.com • (314) 960-2551 • jacoblindsey.netlify.app/

CAREER SUMMARY

Experience 3 years as a Jr. Developer at a local start-up company, 10+ years in a manufacturing leadership role

Languages JS, React, Typescript, Vue, Node.JS, Express, CSS3, HTML5, MongoDB, Python, Angular

Tools Git, GitHub, Webpack, npm, Jest, Photoshop, Illustrator, After-Effects, AutoCAD

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Campfire Studios LLC

St. Louis, MO.

Jr. Developer

03/2013 - 09/2016

Technologies: C#, CSS3, JS, XCode, Angular

- Developed a mobile game for 10+ Midwest based hospitals named "Ivy's House Hunt", used to calm and educate children during I.V. injections and other painful procedures.
- Achieved a 15-20% decrease in time spent sedating patients within 1 year.
- Successfully met each sprint deadline, generating 30% of the company's revenue for that year.
- Designed styles guides and wrote in-house CSS libraries for 3 other products.

Sika Greenstreak St. Louis, MO.

Fabrication Supervisor

02/2009 - 05/2021

- Oversaw 100% of the fabrication process of custom-built construction materials.
- Reviewed and modified AutoCAD models for specialized orders.
- Maintained constant communication with my team and engineers to ensure compliance with the client specification while maintaining a 98% product acceptance rate.

PROJECTS

SockChat 02/2022 - 03/2022

Technologies: JS, React, Express, Socket.io, MongoDB, Mongoose

- Built a real-time chat application with optional data persistence.
- My goal with this was to gain experience keeping real-time data in sync across the UI, DB, and server instances.
- Demo: ssockchat.herokuapp.com/

Invoice Tracker 12/2021 – 01/2022

Technologies: JS, React, CSS Modules

- Implemented an intuitive UI for creating and managing Invoices.
- Developed for a small local water-well drilling business, saving them 20+ hours per month since moving from paper invoices.
- Demo: n-voice.netlifv.app/

Personal Blog 11/2021 – 12/2021

Technologies: JS, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, PassportJS, PUG, Bootstrap

- Minimalist blogging site for personal use in developing public communication skills.
- Utilized PUG to become familiar working with templating engines
- Demo: <u>damp-reef-82599.herokuapp.com/</u>

Craps Game 10/2021 - 12/2021

Technologies: JS, React, MaterialUI

- Full featured recreation of the casino game 'Craps'.
- Built using as few dependencies as needed in order to focus solely on React functionality.
- Demo: <u>craps--game.herokuapp.com/</u>

EDUCATION

The Odin Project 06/2021 - 01/2022

Completed the Full Stack Developer curriculum focusing on: JS, React, Node, Express, REST API, A11y, Webpack, Git, MongoDB, Semantic HTML, OAuth, Writing Documentation, Test-Driven-Development